<section>
  <section ID="1">
    <heading>Introduction</heading>
  <sentence /></section>
  <section ID="2">
    <heading>Methodology</heading>
    <section ID="2.1">
      <heading>The Aquarius simulations</heading>
    <sentence>The Aquarius suite formally consists of six diﬀerent simula- tions of Milky Way sized galaxies, one of which is the central dataset used in this paper.</sentence><sentence>A more detailed description of the simulation can be found in S08, but we review the details relevant to this work here.</sentence><sentence>The Aquarius suite has same cosmological initial con- ditions as that of the Millennium simulation (Springel et al.</sentence><sentence>2005).</sentence><sentence>The initial size of the periodic box was 100 Mpc h−1 Mpc set in a cosmology of Ωm = 0.25, ΩΛ = 0.75, σ8 = 0.9, ns = 1, and Hubble constant H0 = 100 h km s−1 Mpc−1 = 73 km s−1 Mpc−1.</sentence><sentence>We are aware that the value of σ8 = 0.9 is higher than the currently accepted valued of σ8 and could lead to an overestimate of the ages of all candidates since all halos will form at earlier times.</sentence><sentence>In terms of reionization, this means that for a ﬁxed ionizing emissivity proportional to the collapsed fraction, the evolution is shifted to somewhat earlier times, resulting in an earlier overlap epoch (Alvarez et al.</sentence><sentence>2006).</sentence><sentence>Studies by Boylan-Kolchin et al.</sentence><sentence>(2011) predict that this would have a relatively minor eﬀect.</sentence><sentence>The Millennium simulation was searched for halos of roughly Milky Way mass and without massive close neigh- bours in the present day (z = 0).</sentence><sentence>Springel et al.</sentence><sentence>(2008) also checked that the semi-analytic modelling applied to the tar- get haloes predicated them to host late-type galaxies.</sentence><sentence>Other- wise the selection was random.</sentence><sentence>These were then resimulated using 9003 particles in a box of dimension 100 h−1 Mpc.</sentence><sentence>Af- ter identifying the Lagrangian region from when each halo formed, the mass distribution was rerun at a much higher spatial and mass resolution.</sentence><sentence>Although coarse particles were used to sample the distant regions, the resolution was such that the tidal ﬁeld was accurately resolved at all times.</sentence><sentence>The halos labelled, ‘Aq-A’ to ‘Aq-F’, stored snapshots at 128 output times equally spaced in log(a), where a = 1/(1 + z), represents the expansion factor (between redshift between z = 127 and z = 0).</sentence><sentence>In this paper we only focus on the highest resolution halo available, AqA2.</sentence><sentence>Dark matter haloes were identiﬁed using a combination of the friends- of-friends algorithm and subfind (Springel et al.</sentence><sentence>2001).</sentence><sentence>As described in Cole et al.</sentence><sentence>(2008), haloes and their substructure are traced through the snapshots and linked together in a merger tree.</sentence><sentence>The smallest halo able to be resolved in the simulation is of order 105 M⊙.</sentence><sentence>The most pertinent details of the Aquarius simulation used in this study are tabulated in Table 1.</sentence><sentence>For greater detail on the simulation, see S08.</sentence><sentence>2.2</sentence></section>
    <section ID="2.2">
      <heading>Identifying Primordial Globular Clusters</heading>
    <sentence>Independent of whether primordial GCs are signiﬁcant con- tributors to the reionization of the IGM, the precise mech- anism by which they form is still largely unknown.</sentence><sentence>Peebles (1984) was one of the ﬁrst to suggest that GCs may have formed within extended dark matter halos at high redshift.</sentence><sentence>Observations of thin tidal tails by Grillmair et al.</sentence><sentence>(1995) and Odenkirchen et al.</sentence><sentence>(2003) drastically reduced the popularity of this model because it was found by Moore (1996), that tidal tails should not exist if GCs live within extended halos.</sentence><sentence>These studies however, assume that GCs at the present pe- riod represent the environment from which they were born.</sentence><sentence>There is currently no solid evidence to suggest that because GCs today aren’t observed to contain signiﬁcant traces of dark matter, that their more massive progenitors did not form within dark matter either.</sentence><sentence>More recent work has renewed interest in the dark halo- GC formation scenario due to a range of numerical works published over the past decade (Bromm &amp; Clarke 2002, Mashchenko &amp; Sills 2005, Bekki &amp; Yahagi 2006, Bekki et al.</sentence><sentence>2007, Boley et al.</sentence><sentence>2009, Carretta et al.</sentence><sentence>2010).</sentence><sentence>From a dy- namical evolution standpoint, if GCs were in fact 8-25 times larger when formed than observed at present (Schaerer &amp; Charbonnel 2011), the likelihood of a giant molecular cloud (fsfe ∼ 0.3) of ∼ 109 M⊙ collapsing without being embed- ded within any dark halo is at this stage, small.</sentence><sentence>Bromm &amp; Clarke (2002) and Mashchenko &amp; Sills (2005) have also shown that it is possible for the extended halos of GCs to be tidally stripped away by the present day.</sentence><sentence>More recently, Boley et al.</sentence><sentence>(2009) carried out studies of the radial distri- bution of bright GCs in the Milky Way and concluded that it is possible that they formed in biased dark matter halos at high redshift.</sentence><sentence>The formation of multiple stellar popula- tions within GCs (Bekki &amp; Yahagi 2006, Bekki et al.</sentence><sentence>2007 and Carretta et al.</sentence><sentence>2010) are also consistent with the dark halo-GC formation channel.</sentence><sentence>In our work, we assume that high-z GCs did form within the very ﬁrst collapsed minihalos and due to dynamical dis- ruption and violent relaxation, have since lost their dark matter halos.</sentence><sentence>This assumption also makes it possible to model them as sources of reionization in current dark-matter only, ΛCDM simulations relatively straightforwardly.</sentence><sentence>c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 4 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>Table 1.</sentence><sentence>The basic parameters of the Aquarius simulation data used in this paper.</sentence><sentence>Name mp ϵ Nhr Nlr M200 r200 M50 r50 N50 [M⊙] [pc] [M⊙] [kpc] [M⊙] [kpc] Aq-A2 1.370 × 104 65.8 531,570,000 75,296,170 1.842 × 1012 245.88 2.524 × 1012 433.52 184,243,536 Notes: mp is the particle mass, ϵ is the Plummer equivalent gravitational softening length, Nhr is the number of high resolution particles, and Nlr the number of low resolution particles ﬁlling the rest of the volume.</sentence><sentence>M200 is the virial mass of the halo, deﬁned as the mass enclosed in a sphere with mean density 200 times the critical value.</sentence><sentence>r200 gives the corresponding virial radius.</sentence><sentence>We also give the mass and radius for a sphere of overdensity 50 times the critical density, denoted as M50 and r50.</sentence><sentence>Note that this radius encloses a mean density 200 times the background density.</sentence><sentence>Finally, N50 gives the number of simulation particles within r50.</sentence><sentence>Our primary model of globular cluster formation is the same as that found in Section 2.2 of G10.</sentence><sentence>In this work how- ever, we focus on metal-poor GC production only but sig- niﬁcantly improve on the previous work.</sentence><sentence>We focus on metal- poor GC formation because their relative spread of ages (De Angeli et al.</sentence><sentence>2005) places them coincidentally at the ideal time to be signiﬁcant contributors to the reionization pro- cess.</sentence><sentence>We adopt a relatively simple model to identify where the metal-poor GC objects would form within the Aquar- ius simulation based on the requirements for the collapse of a proto-GC gas cloud.</sentence><sentence>The majority of previous studies adopt a similar model for GC formation, but the resolution of the Aquarius simulation allows us to directly measure the primary parameter; temperature.</sentence><sentence>Nishi (2002) and several others found that in order for gas clouds to eﬃciently cool, they must facilitate one or a combination of the three mechanisms; collisional excitation of hydrogen and helium, radiative recombination of hydro- gen, and bremsstrahlung.</sentence><sentence>The typical cooling function for a proto-GC candidate reveals an immense increase in the cooling rate as the temperature reaches 104 K, critical to the formation of stars.</sentence><sentence>Assuming the gas is in quasi-static equilibrium with the dark matter, we can use the virial theorem to relate the 1D velocity dispersion of the dark matter halos to temperature.</sentence><sentence>The ratio of the 1-D internal velocity dispersion of the dark matter subhaloes (σv) to the inferred virial temperature of the gas, Tv is given by; σ2 v = kTv µmH , (1) where mH is the mass of a hydrogen atom and µ is the mean molecular weight of the gas.</sentence><sentence>We adopt molecular weight of µ = 0.58, appropriate for a fully-ionized, primordial gas.</sentence><sentence>Using these values, we therefore assume that whenever a halo’s velocity dispersion increased above 11.9 kms−1 (Tv ∼ 104 K), it is a GC candidate.</sentence><sentence>The smallest halo identiﬁed via this method contains 1619 particles, corresponding to a dark matter mass of 2.17 × 107 M⊙.</sentence><sentence>Throughout this work, ‘MPGCs’ and ‘GCs’ represent the exact same objects, metal- poor globular clusters.</sentence><sentence>2.3</sentence></section>
    <section ID="2.3">
      <heading>Treatment of GCs as ionizing Sources</heading>
    <sentence>The Aquarius simulation allows us to identify where and when candidate sources (i.e.</sentence><sentence>GCs) will form and our photon- conserving, three dimensional, non-equilibrium chemistry code (C2-Ray, Mellema et al.</sentence><sentence>2006) will ensure the radi- ation from these sources is treated accurately.</sentence><sentence>2.3.1 Radiative Transfer Calculations C2-Ray is a grid-based short characteristics ray-tracing code which is photon conserving and traces rays away from our GC sources up to each cell.</sentence><sentence>Photon conservation is assured by adopting a ﬁnite-volume approach when calculating the photoionization rates and by using time-averaged optical depths.</sentence><sentence>Although helium is not modelled directly in this work, C2-Ray assumes that where and when hydrogen is ionized, helium is once (but not twice) ionized because of the similar ionization potentials of hydrogen and helium-I.</sentence><sentence>The evolution of the ionized fraction of hydrogen, xi, (in- cluding recombinations) is governed by, dxi dt = (1 − xi)(Γi + neCi) − xineαB (2) where ne is the electron density, Γi is the photo-ionization rate, Ci is the collisional ionization rate and αB is the recom- bination rate.</sentence><sentence>The code has been tested against 9 other rival ray tracing codes and was found to be on par with the best codes available today (Iliev et al.</sentence><sentence>2006, Iliev et al.</sentence><sentence>2009).</sentence><sentence>For more details, see Mellema et al.</sentence><sentence>(2006) and references therein.</sentence><sentence>A density mesh at both 2563 and 5123 resolutions of the AqA2 halo was created for each time step using a Cloud-in- Cell algorithm centred on the central host maintaining a physical volume of 6 h−1 Mpc.</sentence><sentence>This means that the cell width for our high resolution run is 11 h−1 kpc/cell, sig- niﬁcantly more accurate than the 195 h−1kpc/cell used in Lunnan et al.</sentence><sentence>(2012).</sentence><sentence>Since the Aquarius simulation con- sists of both high and low resolution particles in the same volume, composite positions of all types of particles were used to ensure the density was properly represented at all spatial scales.</sentence><sentence>2.3.2 Mapping Sources Potential GC formation sites were located via the prescrip- tion previously discussed (see Subsection 2.2) through SQL queries of the publicly availably Aquarius database1.</sentence><sentence>These were then mapped into a grid based mesh for radiative pro- cessing according to the run’s resolution.</sentence><sentence>If more than one 1 Aquarius database; http://www.galaxy-catalogue.dur.ac.uk :8080/Aquarius/ c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 The inhomogenous reionization of the IGM by MPGCs 5 halo was identiﬁed within the same cell, those halos were combined and a luminosity assigned following a prescription based on their combined mass.</sentence><sentence>For the 2563 simulation, we found that only eight GC candidates formed within the same cell as another.</sentence><sentence>When the resolution was increased to 5123, no two GCs were found to have formed within the same grid cell (i.e.</sentence><sentence>every GC was unique within its own grid cell).</sentence><sentence>The completeness of the identiﬁed sources is not homo- geneous across the C2-Ray box.</sentence><sentence>Since the Aquarius volume was resimulated in a Lagrangian volume, the total volume in which sources can be identiﬁed is less than the total volume of the box used by C2-Ray.</sentence><sentence>This incompleteness near the edges is yet another reason to restrict analysis to only those sources which have merged with the central halo.</sentence><sentence>Despite having minor source incompleteness just near the edge of the C2-Ray volume, the density ﬁeld in these outer regions is still accurately represented since the particles which cre- ated the mesh span the entire volume (high-resolution and low-resolution).</sentence><sentence>2.3.3 Calculating The Total Escape Fraction, fγ As highlighted by Ricotti (2002) and Schaerer &amp; Charbon- nel (2011), the primary problem with all GCs studies is that there is signiﬁcant uncertainty in the emissivity of GCs in the early universe.</sentence><sentence>Exactly how many photons are produced in GCs over time depends largely on three parameters; what fraction of the gas is converted into stars fsfe, how eﬀec- tive are the stars at producing ionizing photons ¯q, which reach the intergalactic medium and ﬁnally, what fraction of the photons manage to escape the collapsing giant molec- ular cloud fesc.</sentence><sentence>We parameterize all of these with a single parameter, fγ (fγ = ¯q × fsfe × fesc) which is equivalent to the number of ionizing photons/atom entering the IGM (be- tween time steps).</sentence><sentence>Since the code is suﬃciently fast and the number of ionizing sources is relatively small, several runs of varying fγ values were able to be completed.</sentence><sentence>Baumgardt &amp; Kroupa (2007) found that in order to form a bound cluster, the star formation eﬃciency had to be one third or more.</sentence><sentence>If all of the gas in a halo does not end up in the proto-cluster, the SFE could be considerably lower.</sentence><sentence>The range of plausible values of the SFE adopted were, 0.15 &lt; fsfe &lt; 0.7.</sentence><sentence>Yajima et al.</sentence><sentence>(2011) recently combined three dimen- sional radiative transfer calculations and a cosmological smooth particle hydrodynamic simulation to study the es- cape fraction, fesc, of ionizing photons of high redshift galax- ies.</sentence><sentence>They found that the escape fraction drastically increased towards decreasing mass with halos of mass &lt;109 M⊙ hav- ing an average fesc ∼ 0.4.</sentence><sentence>As described in Ricotti (2002), dust extinction and large levels of radiation are absorbed by the molecular cloud could drastically reduce this value.</sentence><sentence>Our adopted escape fractions, ranging from photon-poorest to photon-richest scenario, were 0.1 &lt; fesc &lt; 0.7.</sentence><sentence>As in G10, we use the the Population II eﬃciency curve of Figure 2 from Tumlinson et al.</sentence><sentence>(2004) (calculated using the STARBURST99 code of Leitherer et al.</sentence><sentence>1999) to cal- culate the number of ionizing photons emitted per baryon.</sentence><sentence>Averaging over a Salpeter IMF (see Appendix of Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>2010) gives ¯q ≈ 10 000.</sentence><sentence>This ﬁgure could be raised by moving towards a more top-heavy IMF but recent work by Schaerer &amp; Charbonnel (2011) indicates that the ionizing photon output is quite independent of the IMF slope.</sentence><sentence>Since there are relatively few observational constraints on the escape fraction and star formation eﬃciency at high redshift, the total escape fraction, fγ, is largely a free pa- rameter with signiﬁcant uncertainty.</sentence><sentence>However, by spanning a wide range of photon eﬃciencies, the consequences of hav- ing photon rich or photon poor metal-poor globular clusters on the reionization of the IGM can be examined without having to know what each of these quantities are exactly.</sentence><sentence>The upper and lower limits of the total number of photons per baryons being produced by GC candidates in this study can be found in Table 2.</sentence><sentence>The total range of fγ values used in this study, ranging from extremely photon-poor to ex- tremely photon-rich, are fγ = 150, 250, 500, 700, 1000 and 5000 photons/baryon.</sentence><sentence>Our primary assumption here is that the baryons follow the underlying dark matter and photons are produced uniformly over a given time step.</sentence><sentence>Any unsup- pressed sources will continue producing photons in the sub- sequent time step.</sentence><sentence>Each simulation has a time step of ∼20 Myrs.</sentence><sentence>In addition to the ionization models already described, we include a ‘truncation model’ whereby halo formation is suppressed beyond a ﬁxed redshift (ztrunc).</sentence><sentence>The only other requirement for these halos is that they have merged with the central halo by the present day (z = 0).</sentence><sentence>G10 originally used this type of suppression model and found a ztrunc = 13 to be the most suitable of the possible truncation redshifts.</sentence><sentence>This truncation redshift can ultimately be arbitrary as it simply depends on the eﬃciency of the sources used.</sentence><sentence>We adopt ztrunc = 13 here for the simple purpose of illustrat- ing the eﬀect inhomogeneous ionization models have on the numbers and distributions of GC candidates when compared to a truncation models.</sentence><sentence>2.3.4 Suppression Criterion Throughout this work we deﬁne ‘suppression’ as the inabil- ity of candidate halos to develop into GCs because their gas content is ionized locally.</sentence><sentence>A radiative transfer cell is consid- ered ionized when the ionized fraction of hydrogen is above a ﬁxed threshold (xthresh).</sentence><sentence>Throughout our entire study we set xthresh = 0.1.</sentence><sentence>GC candidates residing in a cell with an ionized fraction above this threshold are suppressed.</sentence><sentence>An increase in the ionized fraction threshold essentially decreases the strength of the suppression process.</sentence><sentence>To gain a full understanding of the subtle diﬀerences in the strength of the suppression on the overall reionization process, a range of ionized fraction thresholds must be tested.</sentence><sentence>In Appendix B of Iliev et al.</sentence><sentence>(2011), they discuss how source suppression de- pends on the Jeans mass suppression threshold.</sentence><sentence>They found both xthresh = 0.1 and 0.5 yield essentially the same IGM evolution, apart from a slight oﬀset in time.</sentence><sentence>Only for xthresh = 0.9 (weak suppression) does the evolution of the IGM be- gin to behave very diﬀerently.</sentence><sentence>However, they were studying the reionization process in large scale galaxy cluster environ- ments and so these inferences do not necessarily translate di- rectly to a smaller Milky Way type environment like the one studied here.</sentence><sentence>The only way to determine the eﬀect of higher ionized fraction thresholds is to do a direct recalculation of one of the runs presented here but with higher threshold values.</sentence><sentence>We defer such a study to future work (see Section c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 6 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>Table 2.</sentence><sentence>The photon-poorest and photon-richest scenarios con- strained by previous computational studies.</sentence><sentence>These limits set the upper and lower bounds on the total number of photons/baryon leaving a proto-GC, fγ, in this study.</sentence><sentence>Parameter Photon-poorest Photon-richest Model Model ¯q 10,000 ph/b 10,000 ph/b fsfe 0.15 0.7 fesc 0.1 0.7 fγ 150 ph/b ∼5000 ph/b 5 for further discussion).</sentence><sentence>In any case, in this work, we only require that a halo is for the ﬁrst time above σ &gt; 11.9 km/s and that it resides within a cell with an ionized fraction, x &lt; 0.1.</sentence><sentence>In terms of computation time, the highest resolution simulations (5123, Model 2: delayed) were carried out in par- allel on 8 nodes, each using 8 cores, requiring 1.2 GB of mem- ory (for all sources) and 9 hours of computation time.</sentence><sentence>The lowest resolution simulation (2563, Model 1: permanently suppressed) took 1 hour of computation time.</sentence><sentence>3 MODEL EXTENSIONS: DELAYED STAR FORMATION &amp; DYNAMICAL DESTRUCTION In this section, we detail two extensions of the previous model; delayed star formation and dynamical disruption.</sentence><sentence>Whilst these processes have been studied before, it is the ﬁrst time that the following two models have been combined together in the context of GC formation.</sentence><sentence>3.1</sentence></section>
  <sentence /></section>
  <section ID="3">
    <heading>Model Extensions: Delayed Star Formation &amp; Dynamical Destruction</heading>
    <section ID="3.1">
      <heading>Delayed Star Formation</heading>
    <sentence>As an extension to the previous model, we made use of the merger trees to trace candidate GCs spatial and dynamical evolution throughout the AqA simulation.</sentence><sentence>In many previous works, the suppression of candidate clusters is treated in a simple, straightforward manner.</sentence><sentence>If a candidate satellite re- sides within an ionised region, it is suppressed permanently.</sentence><sentence>We too adopt this technique for some of our models and class them as ‘Model 1’ or the ‘permanently suppressed’ model.</sentence><sentence>On cosmological scales, such ‘suppressed once-and- forever’ type models are a good approximation since there are many neighbouring sources to keep most regions ionised.</sentence><sentence>Any descendent of a suppressed halo entering one of these ionised regions will remain suppressed.</sentence><sentence>On small scales how- ever, such as the one being dealt with here, there are occa- sions where a candidate GC, previously suppressed, may be able to become active again once its gas content becomes neutral at a later time-step.</sentence><sentence>This process eﬀectively delays the star formation of a GC candidate and adds previously suppressed candidates to the list of legitimate GCs in the present day (z = 0).</sentence><sentence>This important process can be closely examined by using the merger trees of the simulation under study.</sentence><sentence>In this work, we denote this type of model as ‘Model 2’ or the ‘delayed’ model.</sentence><sentence>These names are used interchange- ably though out this work.</sentence><sentence>Our delayed model works as follows.</sentence><sentence>At each snapshot, we add the descendent IDs of each of the active halos to a cumulative list.</sentence><sentence>In the subsequent snapshot, candidate halos are checked against this list to determine if any of the po- tentially active sources have been active before.</sentence><sentence>If a match is found, this halo’s descendent ID is added to the list and it is removed from the potential new sources for that snap- shot.</sentence><sentence>If a match is not found, the ionisation state of the cell that source resides in is checked and if it is neutral (or be- low xthresh = 0.10) it will then become active and the usual quantities propagated.</sentence><sentence>In this way, Model 2 has two types of populations form- ing over the course of the simulation; ‘ﬁrst timers’ (i.e.</sentence><sentence>source which becomes active in the same snapshot they are identiﬁed) and ‘delayed’ (i.e.</sentence><sentence>they become active at a later snapshot than the one they are identiﬁed).</sentence><sentence>This also self- consistently excludes any halos which have any active an- cestors.</sentence><sentence>At early times, one would expect there to be direct overlap of the total number of sources using either Model 1 and Model 2 but once delayed halos add substantial ionising photons to the IGM at later times, this will alter the number and present day properties of the candidates across the two models.</sentence><sentence>In summary, Model 1 (or M1) represents a ‘permen- tantly suppressed’ scenario whereby ionization suppresses a GC candidate permentantly and never ignites at any subse- quent time step.</sentence><sentence>Model 2 (or ‘delayed model’) incorporates all of the same identiﬁcation methods used in Model 1 ex- cept that now the descendents of previously suppressed halos can become active if their gas content becomes suﬃciently neutral and they have no active ancestors.</sentence><sentence>In this work we refer to Model 1 with fγ = 500 (where fesc = 0.2 and fsfe = 0.25) as our ﬁducial model because the adopted total escape fraction is within the reasonable range of literature estimates.</sentence><sentence>Table 3 lists the two types of models tested and the range of photoionisation eﬃciencies adopted in this work (e.g.</sentence><sentence>our ﬁducial model is represented by M1 512 ph500; Model 1 at 5123 resolution with fγ = 500).</sentence><sentence>3.2</sentence></section>
    <section ID="3.2">
      <heading>Dynamical Destruction</heading>
    <sentence>In the second extension to our model, we address the im- portant process of dynamical destruction.</sentence><sentence>Although we have excellent resolving power to locate where candidates form, it is impossible to locate these halo structures in the present day (z = 0) as the vast majority of them will have undergone mergers with either the host or each other.</sentence><sentence>As with G10, we assume the collapsed baryonic gas fraction of a GC at the centre of each halo will follow the same trajectory as that of the most bound particle of the halo.</sentence><sentence>At each snapshot we simply identify the most bound particle corresponding to each GC candidate.</sentence><sentence>We then follow this most bound par- ticle through to the present day allowing us to track the GC formation sites over the course of the entire simulation.</sentence><sentence>During mergers with the central halo, the formation site is no longer able to be tracked by subfind and so we must infer the trajectory of the formation site within the host halo based on the most bound particle alone.</sentence><sentence>Baumgardt &amp; Makino (2003) derived a ﬁtting formula based on a series of c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 The inhomogenous reionization of the IGM by MPGCs 7 Table 3.</sentence><sentence>The simulation suites used in this study.</sentence><sentence>‘M1’ and ‘M2’ denote Model 1 (permanently suppressed model) and Model 2 (delayed model), respectively.</sentence><sentence>Our ﬁducial model is M1 512 ph500.</sentence><sentence>A lower resolution run (2563) of our ﬁducial model model is also carried out to test for convergence to ensure our results are not resolution dependent (see Sub-section 5.3) .</sentence><sentence>Name # cells fγ [ph/b] M1 512 ph150 5123 150 M1 512 ph250 5123 250 M1 256 ph500 2563 500 M1 512 ph500 5123 500 M1 512 ph700 5123 700 M1 512 ph1000 5123 1000 M1 512 ph5000 5123 5000 M2 512 ph150 5123 150 M2 512 ph250 5123 250 M2 512 ph500 5123 500 M2 512 ph700 5123 700 M2 512 ph1000 5123 1000 M2 512 ph5000 5123 5000 N-body models to determine whether a star cluster, given a few basic orbital characteristics, will be disrupted during its orbit around a host after such an encounter takes place.</sentence><sentence>The expression they derived (Equation 10 from Baumgardt &amp; Makino 2003) for the dissolution time was, Tdiss = β � M 0.33 M⊙ �x RG kpc � VG 220 km s−1 �−1 (1 − ϵ), (3) where M is the halo mass before infall, ϵ is the orbital ec- centricity, RG is the apocentric distance of the halo (kpc), VG is the circular velocity (km/s) of the host galaxy and x and β are cluster scaling law parameters depending on the cluster concentration.</sentence><sentence>From a ﬁt to the lifetimes of the King (1966) models with dimensionless central potential W0=5.0, Baumgardt &amp; Makino (2003) found x = 0.75, β = 1.91.</sentence><sentence>For more concentrated, W0 = 7.0 King proﬁle clusters, they found a small change in the dissolution time of a clus- ter (see Fig.</sentence><sentence>3 of Baumgardt &amp; Makino 2003 for details) and so for the sake of simplicity we restrict our dissolution analysis to W0 = 5.0 King proﬁle clusters only.</sentence><sentence>In order to determine whether a candidate GC survives an encounter with the central host halo, its calculated dissolution time must be compared to the time it merged with the central host.</sentence><sentence>If the time since the candidate GC merged with the central halo exceeds its dissolution time, then the cluster is disrupted.</sentence><sentence>4 RESULTS Here we present the results of our simulations organised as follows.</sentence><sentence>Section 4.1 outlines the results for Model 1.</sentence><sentence>Sec- tion 4.2 uses the same candidates identiﬁed in Section 1 but applies the dynamical disruption model outlined in Section 3.2.</sentence><sentence>Finally, Section 4.3 presents the results of Model 2 which includes previously suppressed sources which are allowed to turn on given the correct environmental and antecedent con- ditions.</sentence><sentence>The objects used in all of the following analyses have been restricted to only those which merge with the ﬁnal host by z = 0.</sentence><sentence>Speciﬁcally, merged means that subfind can no longer recognise them as two separate structures in the present day.</sentence><sentence>The total number of objects formed without suppression is 310.</sentence><sentence>Though there are objects which retain their dark matter halos, we cite G10 as a preliminary anal- ysis of these objects and save more detailed study of these survivors for future work.</sentence><sentence>4.1 Model 1: ‘suppressed permentantly’ 4.1.1 Visualisation Of The ionization Field We identify GCs using the method described in Section 2.2 and show a visual representation of these candidates ionizing the IGM in Figures 1 and 2.</sentence><sentence>Figure 1 shows the neutral gas density using a ﬁxed emissivity of fγ = 500 photons/baryon at z = 14.03, 12.07, 8.90, 7.03 within a box of 63 h−3 Mpc3.</sentence><sentence>This shows a clear evolution of the ionizing fronts through- out the IGM during the formation of the proto-Milky Way particularly highlighting the inhomogeneous nature of the ionization ﬁeld.</sentence><sentence>Figure 2 shows six runs at diﬀering emissiv- ities all captured at the same time (z = 10.11).</sentence><sentence>The emis- sivities range from fγ = 150 to fγ = 5000 and clearly illus- trates how higher photo-ionization eﬃciencies ionize larger volumes.</sentence><sentence>Interestingly the very central regions of the host galaxy remain relatively neutral (R &lt; 100 kpc).</sentence><sentence>An increase in the local recombination rate (∝ ρ2) in this region makes it diﬃcult for central region to become ionized.</sentence><sentence>4.1.2 Formation History &amp; Numbers The formation history and overall numbers in each of our models are shown in Figure 3.</sentence><sentence>GC formation without sup- pression is shown by the open bins outlining each of the sup- pression models (shown in colour).</sentence><sentence>As expected, the relative numbers of objects at high-redshift are similar as the forma- tion environments are roughly the same.</sentence><sentence>As the activation of more sources proceeds, large quantities of ionizing photons are injected into the IGM resulting in greater suppression in the higher escape fraction models than the lower escape fraction models.</sentence><sentence>This amount of suppression taking place is most signiﬁcant at z &lt; 16.</sentence><sentence>There are no active sources in any of the models below z = 8 except for one lone source forming at z = 5 in the photon-poor, M1 512 ph150 model.</sentence><sentence>Figure 4 shows the cumulative total of GCs forming indicating a factor of ∼3 diﬀerence in total number from the lowest (fγ = 150 photons/baryon) to the highest (fγ = 5000 photons/baryon) ionization eﬃciency.</sentence><sentence>Table 4 shows the total number of objects formed and suppressed over the entire simulation for diﬀerent photo- ionization eﬃciencies.</sentence><sentence>As expected, there is a drastic depen- dence of the suppression rate on the ionization eﬃciency.</sentence><sentence>The number of objects which form between the photon-poor (fγ = 150) and photon-rich (fγ = 5000) environments in our models diﬀer by a factor of 2.7.</sentence><sentence>4.1.3 Ages As illustrated by the open bins in Figure 3, the identiﬁcation of GC candidates extends down to z = 4.</sentence><sentence>Through the pro- cess of self-ionization, the potential number of GCs drasti- c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 8 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>Figure 1.</sentence><sentence>Time evolution of the ionization ﬁeld.</sentence><sentence>Each panel represents a spatial slice (x-y projection), 460 h−1kpc thick, of the ionized and neutral gas density from simulations of Model 1 using photo-ionization eﬃciencies of fγ = 500 at z = 14.03, 12.07, 8.90 and 7.03 respectively.</sentence><sentence>The box in each panel has a comoving width of 6 h−1 Mpc.</sentence><sentence>Figure 2.</sentence><sentence>Snapshots of the ionization ﬁeld for the six photo-ionization eﬃciencies tested in this study all taken at the same redshift (z = 10.11).</sentence><sentence>Again, each panel represents a spatial slices (x-y projection), 460 h−1kpc thick, of the ionized and neutral gas density from simulations of Model 1.</sentence><sentence>Top left to top right: fγ = 150, 250, 500 photons/baryon and bottom left to bottom right: fγ = 700, 1000 and 5000 photons/baryon.</sentence><sentence>The box in each panel has a comoving width of 6 h−1 Mpc.</sentence><sentence>cally decreases due to the ionization ﬂux from the ﬁrst group of active sources.</sentence><sentence>This process pushes back the average age of each of the GC populations.</sentence><sentence>The mean age (calculated assuming a ﬂat cosmology) for Model 1 is shown in Table 5.</sentence><sentence>Overall, a higher the ionization eﬃciency will lead to, on av- erage, older GCs due to the wiping out of potential sources at low redshift.</sentence><sentence>The youngest population on average is the population resulting from the M1 512 ph150 model, having an average age of 13.30 Gyrs whilst the oldest population on average is the M1 512 ph150 model, having an average age of 13.42 Gyrs.</sentence><sentence>Whilst each of the model GC population’s formation is extended in redshift-space, the corresponding age range they occupy is quite narrow (mean = 13.39 Gyr, σ = 0.04 Gyr).</sentence><sentence>The surviving GCs in all of the models have mean ages consistent with the Galactic MPGC ages deter- mined from the Advanced Camera for Surveys (ACS) survey carried out by Mar´ın-Franch et al.</sentence><sentence>(2009) (13.5 ± 1.5 Gyrs) and other MPGC age studies (z &gt; 5, Fan et al.</sentence><sentence>2006).</sentence><sentence>c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 The inhomogenous reionization of the IGM by MPGCs 9 0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16 18 20 22 24 0 5 10 15 20 25 30 35 40 Number redshift M1_512_ph150 M1_512_ph250 M1_512_ph500 M1_512_ph700 M1_512_ph1000 M1_512_ph5000 potential sources Figure 3.</sentence><sentence>Formation histograms for each of the respective ionization eﬃciencies.</sentence><sentence>The number of objects as a function of redshift are binned in whole integer redshifts for each snapshot of the simulation.</sentence><sentence>For ever higher ionization eﬃciencies, more photons escape into the IGM, resulting in fewer objects forming at lower redshift (i.e.</sentence><sentence>only those identiﬁed by the velocity-temperature criterion from Aquarius) due to to an increased level of suppression.</sentence><sentence>The clear histogram represents the formation of GCs without suppression included.</sentence><sentence>Table 4.</sentence><sentence>The number of active and suppressed sources of each of the various escape fractions and their corresponding suppression rates.</sentence><sentence>Model # Active # Suppressed Suppression Name GCs GCs Rate [%] no suppression 310 0 0 M1 512 ph150 112 198 0.64 M1 512 ph250 103 207 0.67 M1 512 ph500 75 235 0.76 M1 512 ph700 72 238 0.77 M1 512 ph1000 57 253 0.82 M1 512 ph5000 42 268 0.86 Table 5.</sentence><sentence>Mean formation redshift and percentile ages for our metal-poor GCs candidates in each model (assuming a ﬂat cos- mology).</sentence><sentence>Model zmean Percentile Age [Gyrs] Name Formation 10% 50% 90% no suppression 12.25 12.82 13.20 13.36 M1 512 ph150 12.92 12.87 13.23 13.36 M1 512 ph250 13.31 12.92 13.25 13.38 M1 512 ph500 13.56 12.94 13.25 13.39 M1 512 ph700 13.75 13.01 13.25 13.39 M1 512 ph1000 13.92 13.01 13.27 13.39 M1 512 ph5000 14.05 13.01 13.27 13.39 0 5 10 15 20 25 0 50 100 150 200 250 300 350 Number redshift M1_512_ph150 active M1_512_ph150 supp.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph250 active M1_512_ph250 supp.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph500 active M1_512_ph500 supp.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph700 active M1_512_ph700 supp.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph1000 active M1_512_ph1000 supp.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph5000 active M1_512_ph5000 supp.</sentence><sentence>all candidates Figure 4.</sentence><sentence>Cumulative formation history for each of the respec- tive ionization eﬃciencies.</sentence><sentence>Solid lines represent active sources and dashed lines represent suppressed sources.</sentence><sentence>The solid black line represents the formation of all potential cluster candidates iden- tiﬁed within the Aq-A2 simulation.</sentence><sentence>4.1.4 Spatial Distribution Figure 5 shows the z = 0 radial distributions of the GCs in our simulations in both raw number and as a fraction of the total number.</sentence><sentence>These were obtained by following the most-bound particle of each of the candidates once they had merged with the central halo through to the present day (see Section 3.2 for details).</sentence><sentence>The most immediate ob- servation of the is the lack of surviving sources in the inner c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 10 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>50 kpc.</sentence><sentence>Even for the most conservative reionization model (M1 512 ph150), there are ∼20 too few objects to reconcile the radial distribution of the AqA2 halo’s MPGC distribu- tion with that of the Milky Way’s.</sentence><sentence>Another signiﬁcant feature is the diﬀerence in shape of the radial distributions of the inhomogenous ionization mod- els (i.e.</sentence><sentence>models using C2-Ray) and the truncation model (i.e.</sentence><sentence>using ztrunc).</sentence><sentence>The truncation model’s additional GC numbers in the central region originate from the inclusion of all potential sources before z = 13 which are unavail- able to the models using C2-Ray.</sentence><sentence>As Figure 3 illustrates, there are a number of potential sources between z = 23 – 13 which are otherwise suppressed in the inhomogeneous ion- ization models.</sentence><sentence>These halos, having been included in the candidate sample in the truncation model reveal themselves in the central regions of the spatial distribution at z = 0.</sentence><sentence>This highlights the ﬁrst, primary result of this work which is that by treating the ionization ﬁeld inhomogenous man- ner, it results in signiﬁcantly diﬀerent total numbers and z = 0 radial distributions of potential GCs when compared to a model adopting arbitrary truncation.</sentence><sentence>A Kolmogorov Smirnov (KS) test carried out comparing the six C2-Ray distributions against the Milky Way MPGCs ([Fe/H] &lt; -1) found all models except the M1 512 ph150 and M1 512 ph250 models are inconsistent with the Milky Way metal-poor GC distribution at the 1% conﬁdence level.</sentence><sentence>It must be restated that none of the models are designed to replicate the distributions of the Milky Way and these results only show these two of the six distributions (photon- rich models) are statistically consistent with the Milky Way’s MPGC system.</sentence><sentence>It is possible that since we are only using one Aquarius halo that our conclusions are susceptible to scatter.</sentence><sentence>Lunnan et al.</sentence><sentence>(2012) found that the halo-halo scatter from the six Aquarius halos is up to a factor of 2–3.</sentence><sentence>This is an impor- tant caveat of this work and means that in order to get a proper handle on scatter of this distribution, more Milky Way-type galaxies need to be examined.</sentence><sentence>Further discussion of this scatter is discussed in Section 5.</sentence><sentence>The time scale for dynamical friction (Chandrasekhar 1943) is inversely proportional to mass, so the GCs will be more aﬀected by this process than the dark matter parti- cles (which are of order 100 times less massive).</sentence><sentence>For GCs of mass a few times 105M⊙ at radii of 10 kpc the dynamical friction time scale is 1012 years, so this is unlikely to aﬀect our results.</sentence><sentence>4.1.5 Contribution To ionization Of IGM Figure 6 shows the enclosed mass and volume ionized of each of the six models within a comoving box width (centred on the host galaxy) spanning 1 – 6 h−1 Mpc.</sentence><sentence>Within the largest box size, the amount of volume and mass ionized is small compared to the amount of volume and mass ionized in a small box.</sentence><sentence>This is because candidate formation density is largest in the central most dense region of the simulation.</sentence><sentence>Since a large box width encloses signiﬁcantly more baryons than a small box, the total volume and mass fraction ion- ized is lower.</sentence><sentence>As the box width decreases the amount of volume and mass ionized increases as expected.</sentence><sentence>Similarly as the photo-ionization eﬃciency (fγ) increases, the fraction of volume and mass of the respective enclosed volume also 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 140 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 Number R/kpc M1_512_ph150 M1_512_ph250 M1_512_ph500 M1_512_ph700 M1_512_ph1000 M1_512_ph5000 truncated at z = 13 Milky Way GCs [Fe/H] &lt; −1 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 140 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 f (&lt; R) R/kpc M1_512_ph150 [1, 0.000] M1_512_ph250 [1, 0.002] M1_512_ph500 [0, 0.020] M1_512_ph700 [0, 0.020] M1_512_ph1000 [0, 0.160] M1_512_ph5000 [0, 0.670] truncated at z = 13 [0, 0.136] Milky Way GCs [Fe/H] &lt; −1 Figure 5.</sentence><sentence>Radial distribution of candidate GCs in both raw num- ber and normalised to the total number.</sentence><sentence>The thick black line rep- resents the Milky Way’s metal-poor GC distribution.</sentence><sentence>In addition to the six ionization models, the black dashed line represents the truncation model (i.e.</sentence><sentence>GCs in the sample have formed before z = 13 and have merged with the central halo by z = 0).</sentence><sentence>The legend also shows the results from a two-sampled Kolmogorov-Smirnov test carried out between the Milky Way metal-poor distribution and each of the respective models.</sentence><sentence>Each number corresponds to [H, p] where H = 1 if the test rejects the null hypothesis that they are drawn from the same distribution at the 1% signiﬁcance level and p is the asymptotic p-value.</sentence><sentence>increases as expected.</sentence><sentence>In the extremely photon rich model (M1 512 ph5000), as much as 80% of the entire simulated is ionized by z = 10.</sentence><sentence>In terms of volume, 60% and 98% of the 23 h−3 Mpc3 volume centred on the AqA halo is fully ionized by z = 10 for the photon-poorest (M1 512 ph150) and photon-richest (M1 512 ph5000) models, respectively.</sentence><sentence>In terms of the to- tal mass ionized, 50% and 90% of the total mass within the same volume was ionized by z = 10 for the photon-poor and photon-rich models, respectively.</sentence><sentence>The subsequent decrease in the ionized mass fraction is due to the material recom- bining at low redshift.</sentence><sentence>The ionized volume however, remains relatively constant beyond z = 8 since there are fewer sources below this time to increase the ionized volume fraction.</sentence><sentence>The number of ionizing photons emitted by all active sources is plotted in Figure 8.</sentence><sentence>The most eﬃcient of our mod- c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 The inhomogenous reionization of the IGM by MPGCs 11 0 5 10 15 20 25 0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1 redshift xv M1_512_ph150 M1_512_ph250 M1_512_ph500 M1_512_ph700 M1_512_ph1000 M1_512_ph5000 0 5 10 15 20 25 0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1 redshift xm M1_512_ph150 M1_512_ph250 M1_512_ph500 M1_512_ph700 M1_512_ph1000 M1_512_ph5000 Figure 7.</sentence><sentence>Redshift evolution of the volume (xv) and mass (xm) fraction ionized within a 23 h−3 Mpc3 box centred on the host galaxy for each of the respective photo-ionization eﬃciencies.</sentence><sentence>Whilst a signiﬁcant quantity of the enclosed volume is ionized across each of the models, recombinations at low redshift decrease the mass fraction ionized since the number of active sources below z &lt; 10 drastically reduces.</sentence><sentence>In the late reionization era, overlap by neighbouring ionizing sources would ensure the remaining neutral gas becomes ionized by z = 0 (see Iliev et al.</sentence><sentence>2011).</sentence><sentence>els peaks at 1070 photons being produced over the course of the simulation.</sentence><sentence>The active sources in our photon poorest model produces approximately 1068.5 photons within the to- tal 63 h−3 Mpc3 volume.</sentence><sentence>The primary result from this analysis is that if MPGCs did form via the mechanism tested, then at worst, MPGCs contributed a non-trivial fraction (⩾ 40%, Figure 7) of the total ionization of the IGM within a distance of ∼1 h−1 Mpc of the Milky Way 4.2 Extensions to the Model: Dynamical Disruption &amp; Delayed GC Formation In this subsection we discuss extensions to the model.</sentence><sentence>In order to fully appreciate the eﬀect dynamical disruption and delayed formation have on cluster properties, we present our results separately.</sentence><sentence>0 5 10 15 20 25 66 66.5 67 67.5 68 68.5 69 69.5 70 70.5 71 redshift log10 (Nγ) M1_512_ph150 M1_512_ph250 M1_512_ph500 M1_512_ph700 M1_512_ph1000 M1_512_ph5000 Figure 8.</sentence><sentence>Cumulative number of ionizing photons emitted by MPGC candidates within Aquarius over the course of the simu- lation.</sentence><sentence>4.2.1 Dynamical Disruption In order to better understand the survival rates of MPGCs once they merge into the central host halo, we adopted the dynamical disruption model of Baumgardt &amp; Makino (2003).</sentence><sentence>The details of the method of how we include dynam- ical destruction are discussed in Sub-section 3.2.</sentence><sentence>Using this method, the dissolution times for all of the candidate clus- ters were calculated.</sentence><sentence>Objects which have a dissolution time less than the look-back time to when the merged with the host are disrupted.</sentence><sentence>The accuracy of this type of modelling has not yet been compared with higher resolution analy- ses of small scale hydrodynamic systems and so we present these results well aware of the several caveats involved (see Section 5.4 for details) and use this preliminary work as a launching platform for future research.</sentence><sentence>The sample includes all candidate clusters identiﬁed via the temperature-velocity dispersion threshold discussed in Sub-section 2.2.</sentence><sentence>As shown in Figure 9, just over half (60%) of the clusters identiﬁed, whether they are suppressed or not, will undergo dynamical disruption.</sentence><sentence>Further analysis of dif- ferent King proﬁles indicated only a marginal (±6%) swing in survival probability.</sentence><sentence>Figure 10 presents a percentage break down of what happens to the sources that don’t survive through to the present day.</sentence><sentence>The only two ways of removing sources in this model is by dynamical disruption or suppression by ion- ization.</sentence><sentence>With the exception of the photon-richest model (fγ = 5000), approximately half of the candidate GCs in each model are lost due to dynamical disruption and just un- der half are lost due to suppression via photo-ionization.</sentence><sentence>The reason the suppressed fraction doesn’t increase more signif- icantly as the ionization eﬃciency increases is because the sample only examines the sub-population of clusters which are destroyed (i.e.</sentence><sentence>all candidates of the initial population which were removed via suppression or disruption).</sentence><sentence>For ex- ample, in the less eﬃcient models, more clusters are going to be included in the sample because fewer clusters are sup- pressed at lower redshift.</sentence><sentence>This also means however that a larger percentage of these clusters are susceptible to disrup- tion.</sentence><sentence>c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 12 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>1000700500250150 5000 1 2 3 4 5 6 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 box width [h−1 Mpc] z = 13 fγ xv 1000700500250150 5000 1 2 3 4 5 6 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 box width [h−1 Mpc] fγ xm 1000700500250150 5000 1 2 3 4 5 6 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 box width [h−1 Mpc] z = 10 fγ xv 1000700500250150 5000 1 2 3 4 5 6 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 box width [h−1 Mpc] fγ xm 1000700500250150 5000 1 2 3 4 5 6 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 box width [h−1 Mpc] z = 7 fγ xv 1000700500250150 5000 1 2 3 4 5 6 0 0.25 0.5 0.75 1 box width [h−1 Mpc] fγ xm Figure 6.</sentence><sentence>The fraction of the volume (xv) and mass (xm) ionized at three diﬀerent redshifts (z = 7, 10 and 13) plotted simultaneously against the six diﬀerent photo-ionization eﬃciencies (fγ) and the width of the box surrounding the host halo in comoving coordinates.</sentence><sentence>For each of the models, at a given redshift, a box was drawn around the central host galaxy (to within the nearest cell) and the volume and mass fraction ionized was calculated.</sentence><sentence>Clearly, if MPGCs do form via the dark halo formation channel then their contributions to the ionization of their formation environments is substantial.</sentence><sentence>Interestingly, at low box widths, the ionized mass fraction drops.</sentence><sentence>This is because the number of baryons drastically increases towards the central regions and so the ionizing photons can’t penetrate the inner regions of the halo.</sentence><sentence>As discussed in Sub-section 2.3.2, the source sample could be incomplete at distances greater than 2 h−1 Mpc from the host (i.e.</sentence><sentence>box width &gt; 4 h−1 Mpc) due to the fact the the high resolution volume from which the candidates are identiﬁed is smaller than the total box volume of C2-Ray (the density ﬁeld is still accurately represented at all scales however).</sentence><sentence>1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 0 10 20 30 40 50 60 Number log10[Tdiss]/Myrs Figure 9.</sentence><sentence>Dissolution time of candidate MPGCs which have merged with the central host by z = 0.</sentence><sentence>An object with a dis- solution time less than the look-back time it merged with the central host are disrupted.</sentence><sentence>The drastic decrease in the number of potential clusters (excluding the eﬀect of suppression) has signiﬁcant eﬀects on the spatial distributions of the potential MPGC candidates.</sentence><sentence>Figure 11 plots the radial distribution of each of the models with and without dynamical disruption.</sentence><sentence>Unlike the original model, none of the disruption models are statistically con- sistent Milky Way MPGCs at a 1% signiﬁcance level.</sentence><sentence>In order to gain a more complete understanding of the dynamical processes occurring within the host galaxy after a merger takes place, a full hydrodynamic, high-resolution simulation would be required in order to properly determine the survival rates of GCs.</sentence><sentence>We present these broad brush dynamical destruction results to show in concept, that large quantities of GCs will be destroyed once they merge with the central host galaxy and that their radial distributions are currently irreconcilable with the present day metal-poor Galactic GC population.</sentence><sentence>4.2.2 Model #2: Delayed GC Formation In the results thus far, we have presented the properties of MPGC candidates in the context of a model which sup- presses halos once and permanently.</sentence><sentence>This approximation is accurate so long as there are suﬃciently high numbers of ion- izing photons available to keep the entire volume ionized.</sentence><sentence>If for instance a previously suppressed halo’s descendent’s gas content became neutral such that it could collapse to form a GC, this candidate would be excluded in the previous model.</sentence><sentence>As detailed in Section 3.1, we implement a delayed model c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 The inhomogenous reionization of the IGM by MPGCs 13 150 250 500 700 1000 5000 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 % fγ disrupted suppressed Figure 10.</sentence><sentence>Accounting for the empty or disrupted halos.</sentence><sentence>Each stacked bar represents the percentage fraction lost due to sup- pression and dynamical disruption.</sentence><sentence>With the exception of the photon-richest model (fγ = 5000), approximately half are consis- tently lost due to disruption and just under half are lost due to suppression in each of the respective models.</sentence><sentence>whereby all suppressed candidates are still potential sources provided they a) enter a neutral region of the IGM and b) have no active ancestors.</sentence><sentence>Utilising the merger trees of the AqA2 halo enabled us to implement this model in a rela- tively straight forward manner.</sentence><sentence>Figure 12 compares the formation history of the MPGC candidates in both the permanently suppressed and delayed formation models in relation to their present day and for- mation galactocentric radii.</sentence><sentence>At early times, the source posi- tions between the two models are in exact agreement with one another (red stars within black circles) since the IGM hasn’t begun to be signiﬁcantly ionized.</sentence><sentence>As the ionizing ﬂux from those ﬁrst objects increases over time, the number of suppressed candidates also increases, resulting in a num- ber of extra potential sources which could become active later if the environmental requirements are satisﬁed.</sentence><sentence>The ﬁrst of these sources becomes noticeable at z ∼ 19 whereby a few previously suppressed halos become active.</sentence><sentence>Due to the non-linear nature of the ionizing ﬁeld, these ﬁrst addi- tional sources then lead to more signiﬁcant changes at later times.</sentence><sentence>The majority of delayed candidates activate at z &lt; 8 within a galactocentric distance of R &lt; 300 h−1 kpc.</sentence><sentence>This is a result of there being a large neutral region in the centre due to the recombination rate being larger than the ioniza- tion rate.</sentence><sentence>This neutral region can also be reasonably seen upon a visual inspections of the central region in Figure 2.</sentence><sentence>It is clear that previously suppressed sources are merging into these regions and subsequently meeting the necessary environmental requirements to become active.</sentence><sentence>Figure 13 compares the z = 0 radial distributions of all of the candidate MPGCs (cumulative and normalised) in both the permanently suppressed and delayed formation models.</sentence><sentence>The immediate noticeable diﬀerence is the increase in the number of objects in the central region (R &lt; 40 kpc) in the delayed model when compared to Model 1 of the same ionization eﬃciency.</sentence><sentence>As indicated in Figure 12, the majority of these new candidates are coming from suppressed sources 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 140 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 Number R/kpc 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 140 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 f (&lt; R) R/kpc M1_512_ph150 surv.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph150 total M1_512_ph250 surv.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph250 total M1_512_ph500 surv.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph500 total M1_512_ph700 surv.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph700 total M1_512_ph1000 surv.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph1000 total M1_512_ph5000 surv.</sentence><sentence>M1_512_ph5000 total Milky Way GCs [Fe/H] &lt; −1 Figure 11.</sentence><sentence>Model 1 (permanent suppression) radial distributions of candidate MPGCs in both raw number (top panel) and nor- malised number (bottom panel) for models with (dashed lines) and without (solid lines) dynamical disruption.</sentence><sentence>The eﬀect of the dynamical model is stark.</sentence><sentence>Candidate GC populations in the cen- tral regions are drastically reduced resulting in far more extended radial distributions.</sentence><sentence>For reference, the upper panel has the same legend as the lower panel but we exclude it for clarity.</sentence><sentence>becoming active in within 300 kpc of the host.</sentence><sentence>These delayed halos subsequently merge with the host galaxy and populate galactocentric distances between 0 and 100 kpc.</sentence><sentence>Despite the extra GCs are small galactocentric radio, a KS-test carried out on all six Model 2 distributions rejects the null hypoth- esis that they are drawn from the same distribution as the Milky Way MPGCs at the 1% signiﬁcance level.</sentence><sentence>Figure 14 compares the z = 0 radial distributions of all of the candidate MPGCs in the delayed formation mod- els (solid lines) and the same objects truncated at z = 10 (dashed lines).</sentence><sentence>Whilst the delayed model candidates are far too extended in their entirety, when they are trun- cated their spatial distributions are more closely consistent with the metal-poor GCs of the Milky Way (excluding the M1 512 ph5000).</sentence><sentence>This suggests that if metal-poor GCs did form via the dark halo formation channel, then either ex- ternal ionization (i.e.</sentence><sentence>ionization from the Local Group) or ionization from other unaccounted for sources (e.g.</sentence><sentence>Popula- tion II stars) must dominate the local environment from z c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 14 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>0 5 10 15 20 25 0 500 1000 1500 2000 2500 Rform/kpc redshift Model #1: permanently suppressed Model #2: delayed formation 0 5 10 15 20 25 0 20 40 60 80 100 120 140 Rnow/kpc redshift Model #1: permanently suppressed Model #2: delayed formation Figure 12.</sentence><sentence>Top Panel: Comparison between Model 1 (perma- nently suppressed, solid black circles) and Model 2 (delayed for- mation, red stars) using their respective comoving galactocentric distance at formation and their redshift of formation.</sentence><sentence>Bottom Panel: Similar to the top panel but this time shows the galacto- centric distance at z = 0 and redshift of formation of each of the candidates.</sentence><sentence>There are extra sources forming at z &lt; 8 in Model 2 due to previously suppressed sources becoming active after meet- ing the necessary environmental conditions within R &lt; 300 h−1 kpc of the host galaxy.</sentence><sentence>= 10 onwards in order for their radial distributions to be consistent with that of the Milky Way.</sentence><sentence>5 DISCUSSION In this Section, we discuss the more general achievements and limitations of our models with a particular emphasis on areas of improvement.</sentence><sentence>5.1</sentence></section>
  <sentence /></section>
  <section ID="4">
    <heading>Results</heading>
    <section ID="4.1">
      <heading>Model 1: `suppressed permentantly'</heading>
    <sentence /></section>
    <section ID="4.2">
      <heading>Extensions to the Model: Dynamical Disruption &amp; Delayed GC Formation</heading>
    <sentence /></section>
  <sentence /></section>
  <section ID="5">
    <heading>Discussion</heading>
    <section ID="5.1">
      <heading>Overview</heading>
    <sentence>In our previous work (Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>2010) we set out to build a launching platform for more detailed work.</sentence><sentence>This proof- by-concept work proved fruitful in a few important ways.</sentence><sentence>Through a relatively simple GC formation model, we found that if GCs could have formed (in-part) at the centre of dark halo potentials, then the contributions of metal-poor 0 20 40 60 80 100 0 50 100 150 200 250 300 350 Number R/kpc M1&amp;2_512_ph150 M1&amp;2_512_ph250 M1&amp;2_512_ph500 M1&amp;2_512_ph700 M1&amp;2_512_ph1000 M1&amp;2_512_ph5000 Milky Way GCs [Fe/H] &lt; −1 0 20 40 60 80 100 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 f (&lt; R) R/kpc M1&amp;2_512_ph150 M1&amp;2_512_ph250 M1&amp;2_512_ph500 M1&amp;2_512_ph700 M1&amp;2_512_ph1000 M1&amp;2_512_ph5000 Milky Way GCs [Fe/H] &lt; −1 Figure 13.</sentence><sentence>Cumulative (top panel) and normalised (bottom panel) radial distributions of all photo-ionization eﬃciencies in both Model 1 (permanently suppressed, dashed) and Model 2 (delayed formation, solid).</sentence><sentence>The delayed model adds as much as three times more potential GC candidates than the equivalent fγ permanently suppressed model (Model 1).</sentence><sentence>0 20 40 60 80 100 0 50 100 150 200 250 300 350 Number R/kpc M2_512_ph150 M2_512_ph250 M2_512_ph500 M2_512_ph700 M2_512_ph1000 M2_512_ph5000 Milky Way GCs [Fe/H] &lt; −1 Figure 14.</sentence><sentence>Radial distributions of all photo-ionization eﬃcien- cies in Model 2 (solid) and the same objects truncated at z = 10 (dashed).</sentence><sentence>This shows that a better match to the Milky Way can be obtained if further sources of ionization are added at late redshifts.</sentence><sentence>c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 The inhomogenous reionization of the IGM by MPGCs 15 GCs stemming from these dark halos to the reionization of the IGM was signiﬁcant.</sentence><sentence>Using the cumulative mass of these primordial GCs, we estimated their ionizing ﬂux and came to the conclusion that it would have been possible for GCs to have ionized the entire Milky Way by z = 13 (for fγ = 210).</sentence><sentence>Despite the limited success of the model, there were a few glaring assumptions or limitations.</sentence><sentence>For example, a) 100% of the ionizing ﬂux coming from each GC was assumed to have gone into ionizing the Milky Way, b) only one value for the emissivity of the GCs was examined, c) the state of the IGM was entirely unknown at high redshifts and d) an arbitrary truncation redshift based on relatively naive as- sumptions about the nature of the IGM.</sentence><sentence>This work provided us with the understanding required to develop a more de- tailed reionization model and to look at ways of improving the treatment of the ionization ﬁeld.</sentence><sentence>In this latest work, we improve on all of these areas and more.</sentence><sentence>The ﬁrst immediate diﬀerence is that the ion- ization ﬁeld emanating from the sources is inhomogeneous.</sentence><sentence>This reveals itself in both the visuals of Figure 1 and the ex- tended formation histograms in Figure 3.</sentence><sentence>Another key fea- ture of Figure 3 is that unlike the formation history in G10 and Bekki et al.</sentence><sentence>(2008), MPGC formation is extended in time rather than abruptly ending at one speciﬁc redshift.</sentence><sentence>This extended formation can only come about due to the inhomogeneous way in which the ionization ﬁeld propagates through the bulk IGM.</sentence><sentence>Our models are consistent with the overall picture of extended reionization.</sentence><sentence>For the photon- poorest model (M1 512 ph150), the last source is activated as late as z = 4 whereas in the most photon-rich model (M1 512 ph5000), MPGCs cease forming by z = 7 (see Ta- ble 5).</sentence><sentence>5.2 Globular Cluster Dark Halo Formation Hypothesis Whether or not MPGCs originally formed within dark mat- ter halos is still an open question.</sentence><sentence>In this work we do not necessitate that they do but rather ask what sort of esti- mations can one derive if the dark matter halo formation channel produces distributions similar to observations.</sentence><sentence>We conclude that although some GCs may have formed in dark matter halos and were subsequently stripped upon merging with the central host galaxy, a portion of the Galactic glob- ular cluster population we observe today may have come about by other means (e.g.</sentence><sentence>mergers, giant molecular clouds, tidal tails).</sentence><sentence>In Model 1, even before including eﬀects like dynamical disruption, the radial distributions are either too shallow or don’t contain enough GCs to reproduce the Milky Way distribution (even if one assumes several GCs formed per dark matter halo).</sentence><sentence>Though the delayed model (Model 2) does increase the number of potential sources, a great majority of them don’t populate the required locations in order to reconcile the simulated distribution with the Milky Way MPGC distribution.</sentence><sentence>This however ignores the contribu- tion from external sources inundating the IGM with ionizing photons which would suppress low redshift GCs.</sentence><sentence>If we adopt Model 2 and truncate sources at z = 10, the spatial distri- butions are consistent with that of the Milky Way MPGCs.</sentence><sentence>0 5 10 15 20 25 0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1 f (&gt; z) redshift M1_512_ph500 active M1_512_ph500 suppressed M1_256_ph500 active M1_256_ph500 suppressed all candidates Figure 15.</sentence></section>
    <section ID="5.2">
      <heading>Globular Cluster Dark Halo Formation Hypothesis</heading>
    <sentence /></section>
    <section ID="5.3">
      <heading>Convergence</heading>
    <sentence>test for our ﬁducial model, M1 512 ph500.</sentence><sentence>In terms of the cumulative formation num- ber, the lower resolution, 2563 mesh shows a near-complete agreement with the higher resolution 5123 mesh.</sentence><sentence>A KS test reveals that the hypothesis that they are drawn from the same distribution cannot be rejected at the 5% signiﬁcance level.</sentence><sentence>5.3 An important concern for the models is that the results are not dependent on the resolution of the particular simula- tion used.</sentence><sentence>G10 has already shown that the identiﬁcation of sources is not resolution-limited by comparing the forma- tion history of objects found within the higher resolution AqA2 halo to the lower resolution AqA3 halo.</sentence><sentence>Here, we are interested in the dependence of the results on the resolu- tion used by C2-Ray.</sentence><sentence>In conjunction with each of the 5123 suite of models, a lower-resolution 2563 simulation was car- ried out on our ﬁducial model (M1 512 ph500) to test for convergence.</sentence><sentence>In Figure 15, we present the formation history of metal-poor GCs in our ﬁducial model at both resolutions, 2563 and 5123.</sentence><sentence>Both models are in excellent agreement with one another varying only by few percent in number.</sentence><sentence>A KS- test also veriﬁes that they are consistent with having been drawn from the same distribution at the 5% signiﬁcance level.</sentence><sentence>This agreement shows that the results are not signiﬁ- cantly biased by the resolution of the simulations used.</sentence><sentence>5.4</sentence></section>
    <section ID="5.4">
      <heading>Caveats Of This Work</heading>
    <sentence>Although we have tried to eliminate as many known weak- nesses of the models used in this study, there are still a number of remaining caveats which need to be addressed in future studies to improve upon this work.</sentence><sentence>• Accountability of the ionization sources; whilst the ma- jority of the local ionizing ﬂux will come from low mass dark matter halos in the early Universe as time evolves, each of our models diverges from an accurate account of the true ionizing sources.</sentence><sentence>This is because ﬁeld stars, non- dark matter dominated giant molecular clouds and other such objects will begin to play a dominating role at lower redshifts which are not yet modelled in the current work.</sentence><sentence>In- deed recent work by Iliev et al.</sentence><sentence>(2011); Alvarez et al.</sentence><sentence>(2009) suggests a reionization overlap scenario for the local Milky c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 16 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>Way volume whereby reionization was kickstarted by low mass sources locally, but their eﬀective ﬂux is superseded by with the ionizing ﬂux of the Local Group.</sentence><sentence>Nearby proto- clusters (e.g.</sentence><sentence>Virgo and Fornax) clusters would also have had an appreciable aﬀect at later times.</sentence><sentence>When and where this overlap occurred is critical in understanding the origin of present day satellite structures.</sentence><sentence>• Unmerged GCs; Throughout this work we have limited our sample to include only those which have merged with the central halo by z = 0.</sentence><sentence>This was done to not only ensure an accurate sample but for simplicity.</sentence><sentence>Candidates which do not merge with the central halo by z = 0 could be Galactic dwarf galaxies as they will have retained their dark matter halos, though this is highly speculative.</sentence><sentence>Figure 10 of G10 shows the spatial distribution of these non-merged objects is consistent with those GCs found surrounding neighbour- ing dwarf galaxies (see Mateo 1998).</sentence><sentence>Overall there are 47 distinct halos containing 68 GCs at z = 0, indicating that there has been not only major merging with the central host, but also minor-merging of GCs with proto-dwarf galaxies.</sentence><sentence>Whilst there is suﬃcient research to suggest GCs could have formed in dark matter halos and were subsequently stripped of their outer envelope, it remains unclear where the degen- eracy breaks between GC &amp; dwarf galaxy formation pro- cesses.</sentence><sentence>An examination of these non-merged objects needs to be carried out in a more detailed manner to determine their connection (if any) to the known dark matter domi- nated satellites of Milky Way.</sentence><sentence>• GC formation eﬃciency; All of the work presented here assumes that for every dark matter halo, exactly one GC will form in the centre of its potential well.</sentence><sentence>Given that fragmen- tation of large gas clouds can lead to multiple stellar pop- ulations within a single dark matter halo, it still remains unclear as to exactly how many GCs will form in a given dark halo.</sentence><sentence>In any case, it would only shift the halocentric radii plots upwards and not really have any impact on the structural properties of the distributions.</sentence><sentence>Understanding GC formation eﬃciencies better will lead to better estimates of their overall numbers if they do form via the dark halo for- mation channel.</sentence><sentence>• Statistical limitation using one Aquarius halo; Perhaps one of the biggest drawbacks of this work is that it only ex- amines one Milky Way type galaxy.</sentence><sentence>In order to get a better understanding of the underlying physics involved, a larger sample of Milky Way type galaxies would be required.</sentence><sentence>The statistical variation in the number of satellites in the Aquar- ius simulation has also been shown to vary by a factor of 2 or more (Lunnan et al.</sentence><sentence>2012).</sentence><sentence>The overall conclusion that GCs contributed a non-trivial amount to the reionization of the local IGM would be unlikely to change given that the most conservative of our models reionizes more than 50% both by mass and volume of the local IGM by z = 10 (see Fig.</sentence><sentence>7).</sentence><sentence>Although the Aquarius suite consists of six such simulations, the logistics behind analysing the remaining ﬁve halos was not feasible at this time.</sentence><sentence>• Treatment of dynamical disruption; the exact nature of the dynamical processes inside the central host halo after a halo merges is inherently diﬃcult to treat properly.</sentence><sentence>In our model, we trace the single most bound particle of the in-falling MPGCs.</sentence><sentence>These trace particles could be suscepti- ble to violent dynamical changes within the halo resulting in spatial distributions that might not necessarily reﬂect where the true z = 0 position of the baryonic content ended up.</sentence><sentence>In an improvement to this, one could trace the 10% most bound particles to get a better hold on the z = 0 position of the clusters under study.</sentence><sentence>Whilst we observe that the disruption process is a critical component in determine the ﬁnal z = 0 numbers (e.g.</sentence><sentence>as many as half of the original GC population to have formed at high redshift is destroyed by dynamical disruption), a lot more work needs to be done to more ac- curately determine the degree to which GCs are destroyed over the course of their evolution.</sentence><sentence>• Dependence on ionization cell-fraction threshold; Since our simulations do not (yet) have gas and do not calcu- late the temperature, we use the local ionized fraction as a proxy for the temperature (which has a few uncertainties).</sentence><sentence>At very high redshifts things are reasonably simple since it is typically a simple transition from largely neutral to al- most completely ionized as the ionization front overruns the cell in question.</sentence><sentence>A noted problem is what to do after this point.</sentence><sentence>Since the ionization suppresses the low-mass sources, some regions start to recombine (and cool), which eventu- ally should allow the formation of low-mass sources again, but the question is when does this occur?</sentence><sentence>This is a source of uncertainty and so a number of cell fraction thresholds need to be tested in future work.</sentence><sentence>At the moment, the cell fraction (xthresh) was set to 0.1 for this work but arguments can be made to raise this threshold to higher values of xthresh = 0.5 or even 0.9 (see Appendix B of Iliev et al.</sentence><sentence>2011).</sentence><sentence>Model 1 should be retested using these thresholds to determine how much stochasticity one would expect from varying this threshold.</sentence><sentence>• Clumping; volume averaged recombination rates in an inhomogeneous IGM scale with the clumping factor C = � ρ2� / ⟨ρ⟩2, where the ρ denotes volume averaged densities.</sentence><sentence>In our work, we set C = 1 (no clumping).</sentence><sentence>The dependence of halo suppression for varying degrees of clumping is as yet unknown but will be implemented in subsequent work.</sentence><sentence>Recently, Spitler et al.</sentence><sentence>(2012) combined observations with novel modelling to detect evidence of inhomogeneous reionization by MPGCs on cluster scales.</sentence><sentence>They exploited a fundamental characteristic of galaxy assembly (i.e.</sentence><sentence>spatial biasing and kinematics of MPGCs) to constraint the local reionization epoch around individual galaxies.</sentence><sentence>They found a joint constraint from three galaxies of zreion = 10.5+1.0 −0.9 which agrees well with the latest WMAP constraint on zreion.</sentence><sentence>Interestingly they also found a 1.7σ indication that low-density environments were reionized before medium and high-density environments.</sentence><sentence>These results are consistent with the theory that reionization was prolonged in duration with neutral-gas surviving in high-density environments for ex- tended periods.</sentence><sentence>The redshift range of reionization of the local IGM in this work is consistent with their results to within 1σ.</sentence><sentence>Only recently, have computational developments made possible the ability to simulate vast cosmological volumes with exquisite resolution.</sentence><sentence>Future studies such as the work in this paper could be applied to high resolution cluster envi- ronments to verify the claims made by Spitler et al.</sentence><sentence>(2012).</sentence><sentence>Preliminary work will be carried out on the Millennium-II simulation but more tailored simulations for this type of study would be desirable.</sentence><sentence>c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 The inhomogenous reionization of the IGM by MPGCs 17 6 CONCLUSIONS Over the course of this work, we have drawn a number of im- portant conclusions regarding the reionization of the inter- galactic medium by metal-poor globular clusters.</sentence><sentence>These con- clusions are as follows: (i) Treating the ionization ﬁeld in an inhomogeneous manner results in substantially diﬀerent numbers and spatial distributions.</sentence><sentence>Our basic model adopting this type of treat- ment produces comparable numbers of GC candidates to that of the Milky Way but results in radial distributions which are too shallow.</sentence><sentence>Whilst this model does not rule out possibility of GCs forming inside dark matter halos at high redshift, it does indicate that GCs must have formed via other mechanisms to account for the lack of numbers at low radii in our model.</sentence><sentence>In our so-called ‘delayed model’ where GCs are able to become active after having been previously suppressed, the number of candidate GCs drastically increases.</sentence><sentence>These addi- tional candidates however do not end up residing within the inner, R &lt; 60 kpc, of the host halo at z = 0 and so the re- sulting radial distributions are still not comparable to that of the Milky Way.</sentence><sentence>In the arbitrary truncation model, the radial proﬁles and numbers are comparable to the Milky Way metal-poor GCs.</sentence><sentence>This is because in the truncation model (a) there are extra sources available at high redshift which boosts the number of sources at small radii and (b) it by deﬁnition, totally removes the sources below ztrunc which reduces the number of sources at large radii.</sentence><sentence>This ultimately shows that realistic populations can be produced if external sources dominate the photon budget at later times.</sentence><sentence>Overall, the more sophisticated work in this paper clearly shows that treating the ionization of the local IGM in a spatially inhomogeneous manner leads to the IGM being reionized at diﬀerent places at diﬀerent times which greatly impacts the radial distributions of MPGCs.</sentence><sentence>(ii) Globular clusters injected high numbers of ionizing photons into the IGM at high redshift.</sentence><sentence>Conservative eﬃ- ciency estimates of fγ = 150 photons/baryon would have resulted in MPGCs ionizing more than 50% of the local IGM mass and 60% of the local IGM volume by z = 10 (within an enclosed volume of 23 h−3 Mpc3 centred on the host) and upwards of 98% of the volume and 90% of the mass for the photon-richest model (fγ = 5000 photons/baryon).</sentence><sentence>We also estimate that as many as 1070 photons (minimum: 1068.5 photons) were injected in the IGM from MPGCs alone during the early build up the Milky Way.</sentence><sentence>Such a quantity of photons would surely impact the formation of structures around not only the Milky Way, but other GC rich environ- ments as well.</sentence><sentence>(iii) The suppression rate of MPGCs in our simplest reionization model (M1 512 ph150) was 36 % of a total 310 possible MPGC sources.</sentence><sentence>The number of objects which form between the photon-poor (fγ = 150) and photon-rich (fγ = 5000) environments diﬀers by a factor of 2.7.</sentence><sentence>(iv) The unsuppressed MPGCs in all models have a nar- row age range (mean = 13.34 Gyr, σ = 0.04 Gyr) consistent with current ages estimates of the Milky Way MPGCs.</sentence><sentence>(v) The radial distributions for the M1 512 ph150 and M1 512 ph250 models were the only distributions to be sta- tistically consistent with the distribution of the Milky Way MPGCs at the 1% signiﬁcance level.</sentence><sentence>(vi) In an extension to Model 1, we found that dynamical destruction destroys nearly half (52%) of the total GCs avail- able resulting in a sample of GC candidates which is much smaller in number when compared to the Milky Way metal- poor GCs.</sentence><sentence>A KS-test carried out on all six Model 2 distribu- tions rejected the null hypothesis that they are drawn from the same distribution as the Milky Way MPGCs at the 1% signiﬁcance level.</sentence><sentence>(vii) Allowing suppressed halos to turn on once they sat- isfy the required environmental conditions results in double and some times triple the number of potential GCs having formed.</sentence><sentence>These ‘delayed GCs’ begin forming at z ∼ 19 and continue to form up until the present day.</sentence><sentence>The majority of these objects however form within neutral-gas regions of the simulation volume at z &lt; 8 and at R &lt; 300 h−1 kpc from the host.</sentence><sentence>Due to their late formation times, these objects are most likely self-enriched and are therefore not suitable for comparison to the Milky Way MPGCs.</sentence><sentence>If we impose truncation at z = 10, the photon-rich radial distributions (fγ = 1000−5000 photons/baryon) are consistent with that of the Milky Way.</sentence><sentence>In summary, a number of avenues could be explored in future work.</sentence><sentence>Measurements of the variation in our results across a wide variety of Milky Way-type halos and a number of other sources of reionization should be studied.</sentence><sentence>Further- more, testing a range of formation eﬃciencies, cell fraction thresholds (xthresh) and an improved treatment of the dy- namical disruption will help comprehend the ultimate origin of GCs and the role they played during the epoch of reion- ization.</sentence><sentence>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS We wish to thank Holger Baumgardt for many useful dis- cussions relating to the dynamical models used in this work.</sentence><sentence>The simulations for the Aquarius Project were car- ried out at the Leibniz Computing Center, Garching, Ger- many, at the Computing Centre of the Max-Planck-Society in Garching, at the Institute for Computational Cosmology in Durham, and on the ‘STELLA’ supercomputer of the LO- FAR experiment at the University of Groningen.</sentence><sentence>This work was supported by funding from the Aus- tralian Research Council (grant number DP110102608) and the Science and Technology Facilities Council (grant number ST/F002858/1).</sentence><sentence>ITL and PAT were partially supported by the Science &amp; Technology Facilities Council (grant number ST/I000976/1).</sentence><sentence>Brendan Griﬀen would like to acknowledge the support provided by the University of Queensland via a University of Queensland Postgraduate Scholarship.</sentence><sentence>REFERENCES Alvarez M.</sentence><sentence>A., Busha M., Abel T., Wechsler R.</sentence><sentence>H., 2009, ApJ, 703, L167 Alvarez M.</sentence><sentence>A., Shapiro P.</sentence><sentence>R., Ahn K., Iliev I.</sentence><sentence>T., 2006, ApJ, 644, L101 Barkana R., 2004, MNRAS, 347, 59 Baumgardt H., Kroupa P., 2007, MNRAS, 380, 1589 c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17 18 B.</sentence><sentence>F.</sentence><sentence>Griﬀen et al.</sentence><sentence>Baumgardt H., Makino J., 2003, MNRAS, 340, 227 Bekki K., 2005, ApJ, 626, 93 Bekki K., Yahagi H., 2006, MNRAS, 372 Bekki K., Yahagi H., Nagashima M., Forbes D.</sentence><sentence>A., 2007, MNRAS, 382, L87 Bekki K., Yahagi H., Nagashima M., Forbes D.</sentence><sentence>A., 2008, MNRAS, 387, 1131 Boley A.</sentence><sentence>C., Lake G., Read J., Teyssier R., 2009, ApJ, 706, L192 Boylan-Kolchin M., Bullock J.</sentence><sentence>S., Kaplinghat M., 2011, MNRAS, 415, L40 Bromm V., Clarke C.</sentence><sentence>J., 2002, ApJ, 566, L1 Bromm V., Larson R.</sentence><sentence>B., 2004, ARA&amp;A, 42, 79 Busha M.</sentence><sentence>T., Alvarez M.</sentence><sentence>A., Wechsler R.</sentence><sentence>H., Abel T., Strigari L.</sentence><sentence>E., 2010, ApJ, 710, 408 Carretta E., Bragaglia A., Gratton R.</sentence><sentence>G., Recio-Blanco A., Lucatello S., D’Orazi V., Cassisi S., 2010, Astronomy and Astrophysics Supplement Series, 516, A55+ Chandrasekhar S., 1943, ApJ, 97, 255 Ciardi B., Stoehr F., White S.</sentence><sentence>D.</sentence><sentence>M., 2003, MNRAS, 343, 1101 Cole S., Helly J., Frenk C.</sentence><sentence>S., Parkinson H., 2008, MNRAS, 383, 546 Conroy C., Loeb A., Spergel D.</sentence><sentence>N., 2011, ApJ, 741, 72 Davidsen A.</sentence><sentence>F., Kriss G.</sentence><sentence>A., Zheng W., 1996, Nat., 380, 47 De Angeli F., Piotto G., Cassisi S., Busso G., Recio-Blanco A., Salaris M., Aparicio A., Rosenberg A., 2005, AJ, 130, 116 Fan X., Narayanan V.</sentence><sentence>K., Lupton R.</sentence><sentence>H., Strauss M.</sentence><sentence>A., Knapp G.</sentence><sentence>R., Becker R.</sentence><sentence>H., White R.</sentence><sentence>L., Pentericci L., Leggett S.</sentence><sentence>K., Haiman Z., Gunn J.</sentence><sentence>E., Ivezi´c ˇZ., Schnei- der D.</sentence><sentence>P., Anderson S.</sentence><sentence>F., Brinkmann J., Bahcall N.</sentence><sentence>A., Connolly A.</sentence><sentence>J., 2001, AJ, 122, 2833 Fan X., Strauss M.</sentence><sentence>A., Becker R.</sentence><sentence>H., White R.</sentence><sentence>L., Gunn J.</sentence><sentence>E., Knapp G.</sentence><sentence>R., Richards G.</sentence><sentence>T., Schneider D.</sentence><sentence>P., Brinkmann J., Fukugita M., 2006, ApJ, 132, 117 Furlanetto S.</sentence><sentence>R., Zaldarriaga M., Hernquist L., 2004, ApJ, 613, 1 Griﬀen B.</sentence><sentence>F., Drinkwater M.</sentence><sentence>J., Thomas P.</sentence><sentence>A., Helly J.</sentence><sentence>C., Pimbblet K.</sentence><sentence>A., 2010, MNRAS, 405, 375 Grillmair C.</sentence><sentence>J., Freeman K.</sentence><sentence>C., Irwin M., Quinn P.</sentence><sentence>J., 1995, AJ, 109, 2553 Iliev I.</sentence><sentence>T., Ciardi B., Alvarez M.</sentence><sentence>A., Maselli A., Ferrara A., Gnedin N.</sentence><sentence>Y., Mellema G., Nakamoto T., Norman M.</sentence><sentence>L., Razoumov A.</sentence><sentence>O., Rijkhorst E.-J., Ritzerveld J., Shapiro P.</sentence><sentence>R., Susa H., Umemura M., Whalen D.</sentence><sentence>J., 2006, MNRAS, 371, 1057 Iliev I.</sentence><sentence>T., Mellema G., Shapiro P.</sentence><sentence>R., Pen U.-L., Mao Y., Koda J., Ahn K., 2011, ArXiv e-prints Iliev I.</sentence><sentence>T., Moore B., Gottl¨ober S., Yepes G., Hoﬀman Y., Mellema G., 2011, MNRAS, 413, 2093 Iliev I.</sentence><sentence>T., Whalen D., Mellema G., Ahn K., Baek S., Gnedin N.</sentence><sentence>Y., Kravtsov A.</sentence><sentence>V., Norman M., Raicevic M., Reynolds D.</sentence><sentence>R., Sato D., Shapiro P.</sentence><sentence>R., Semelin B., Smidt J., Susa H., Theuns T., Umemura M., 2009, MNRAS, 400, 1283 King I.</sentence><sentence>R., 1966, AJ, 71, 64 Komatsu E., Dunkley J., Nolta M.</sentence><sentence>R., Bennett C.</sentence><sentence>L., Gold B., Hinshaw G., Jarosik N., Larson D., Limon M., Page L., Spergel D.</sentence><sentence>N., Halpern M., Hill R.</sentence><sentence>S., Kogut A., Meyer S.</sentence><sentence>S., Tucker G.</sentence><sentence>S., Weiland J.</sentence><sentence>L., Wollack E., Wright E.</sentence><sentence>L., 2009, ApJ Supp., 180, 330 Leitherer C., Schaerer D., Goldader J.</sentence><sentence>D., Delgado R.</sentence><sentence>M.</sentence><sentence>G., Robert C., Kune D.</sentence><sentence>F., de Mello D.</sentence><sentence>F., De- vost D., Heckman T.</sentence><sentence>M., 1999, ApJ, 123, 3 Loeb A., Barkana R., 2001, ARA&amp;A, 39, 19 Lunnan R., Vogelsberger M., Frebel A., Hernquist L., Lidz A., Boylan-Kolchin M., 2012, ApJ, 746, 109 Madau P., Haardt F., Rees M.</sentence><sentence>J., 1999, ApJ, 514, 648 Mapelli M., Ferrara A., Pierpaoli E., 2006, MNRAS, 369, 1719 Mar´ın-Franch A., Aparicio A., Piotto G., Rosenberg A., Chaboyer B., Sarajedini A., Siegel M., Anderson J., Bedin L.</sentence><sentence>R., Dotter A., Hempel M., King I., Majewski S., Milone A.</sentence><sentence>P., Paust N., Reid I.</sentence><sentence>N., 2009, ApJ, 694, 1498 Mashchenko S., Sills A., 2005, ApJ, 619, 243 Mateo M.</sentence><sentence>L., 1998, ARA&amp;A, 36, 435 Mellema G., Iliev I.</sentence><sentence>T., Alvarez M.</sentence><sentence>A., Shapiro P.</sentence><sentence>R., 2006, New Astronomy, 11, 374 Moore B., 1996, ApJ, 461, L13 Moore B., Diemand J., Madau Pieroand Zemp M., Stadel J., 2006, MNRAS, 368, 563 Nishi R., 2002, Progress of Theoretical Physics Supple- ment, 147, 1 Ocvirk P., Aubert D., 2011, MNRAS, 417, L93 Odenkirchen M., Grebel E.</sentence><sentence>K., Dehnen W., Rix H.-W., Yanny B., Newberg H.</sentence><sentence>J., Rockosi C.</sentence><sentence>M., Mart´ınez- Delgado D., Brinkmann J., Pier J.</sentence><sentence>R., 2003, AJ, 126, 2385 Peebles P.</sentence><sentence>J.</sentence><sentence>E., 1984, Science, 224, 1385 Power C., Wynn G.</sentence><sentence>A., Combet C., Wilkinson M.</sentence><sentence>I., 2009, MNRAS, 395, 1146 Rees M.</sentence><sentence>J., 1997, in Tanvir N.</sentence><sentence>R., Aragon-Salamanca A., Wall J.</sentence><sentence>V., eds, The Hubble Space Telescope and the High Redshift Universe The Universe at z &gt; 5: When and How Did the ‘Dark Age’ End?.</sentence><sentence>p.</sentence><sentence>115 Ricotti M., 2002, MNRAS, 336, L33 Ricotti M., Ostriker J.</sentence><sentence>P., 2004, MNRAS, 350, 539 Ricotti M., Shull J.</sentence><sentence>M., 2000, apj, 542, 548 Schaerer D., Charbonnel C., 2011, MNRAS, 413, 2297 Sokasian A., Abel T., Hernquist L., Springel V., 2003, MN- RAS, 344, 607 Spitler L.</sentence><sentence>R., Romanowsky A.</sentence><sentence>J., Diemand J., Strader J., Forbes D.</sentence><sentence>A., Moore B., Brodie J.</sentence><sentence>P., 2012, MNRAS, p.</sentence><sentence>2978 Springel V., Wang J., Vogelsberger M., Ludlow A., Jenkins A., Helmi A., Navarro J.</sentence><sentence>F., Frenk C.</sentence><sentence>S., White S.</sentence><sentence>D.</sentence><sentence>M., 2008, MNRAS, 391, 1685 Springel V., White S.</sentence><sentence>D.</sentence><sentence>M., Tormen G., Kauﬀmann G., 2001, MNRAS, 328, 726 Springel et al.</sentence><sentence>2005, Nat., 435, 629 Tumlinson J., Venkatesan A., Shull J.</sentence><sentence>M., 2004, ApJ, 612, 602 Wise J.</sentence><sentence>H., 2012, ArXiv e-prints Yajima H., Choi J.-H., Nagamine K., 2011, MNRAS, 412, 411 c⃝ 2012 RAS, MNRAS 000, 1–17</sentence></section>
  <sentence /></section>
  <section ID="6">
    <heading>Conclusions</heading>
  <sentence /></section>
  <section ID="7">
    <heading>Reference</heading>
  <sentence /></section>
</section>